(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-30T05:49:52.185316",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, deep into your heart,
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that reaches you.
わずか散った淡い片思い 笑い話だね今となれば
A fleeting, pale unrequited love becomes a funny story now.
見るもの全て輝いて見えた あの日々がキレイに笑ってるよ
Everything I saw looked so bright; those days are smiling beautifully.
我慢する事だけ覚えなきゃいけないの?
Do I only have to learn to hold back?
『大人になって頂戴ね?』ならなくていいよ
"Grow up, won't you?" You don't have to.
知らない事ばかり『知らない』なんて言えなくて
There's so much I don't know, but I can't say "I don't know."
『大変お似合いで』嘘ついてゴメンね
"You two look great together," sorry for lying.
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, deep into your heart,
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that reaches you.
つまらない『たてまえ』や嫌な事全部 消してあげるから この音で
I'll erase all boring pretenses and bad things with this sound.
何の取り柄も無い 僕にただ一つ
With no special talents to speak of,
少しだけど出来る事 心躍らせる
there is just one small thing I can do: make your heart race.
飾らない言葉 電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey my honest feelings with electronic sounds.
好きになる事 理由なんじゃなくて
Falling in love isn't about reasons,
『こじつけ』なんて要らないんじゃない?
you don't need any forced justifications.
時代のせいと 諦めたらそこまで
If you give up and blame the times, that's the end of it.
踏み出さなくちゃ 何も始まらない
Nothing starts unless you take a step forward.
『ゴメンね夜遅く 寝るところだったでしょ?』
"Sorry for calling so late, were you going to bed?"
『驚いた私も 掛けようとしてた』
"I was surprised, I was just about to call you too."
心の裏側をくすぐられてるような 惹かれ合う2人に 幸せな音を
Giving a happy sound to two people drawn together, tickling their hearts.
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね楽しくなるよ
Happy Synthesizer, see? It's getting fun.
涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
I'll play a melody to wipe away tears.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない 別に自分に素直になればいい
You don't have to act tough, just be true to yourself.
何の取り柄も無い 僕にただ一つ
With no special talents to speak of,
少しだけど出来る事 ちょっと照れるような
there's just one small thing I can do, slightly embarrassing—
単純な気持ち 電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey these simple feelings through electronic sounds.
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, deep into your heart,
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that reaches you.
つまらない『たてまえ』や嫌な事全部 消してあげるから この音で
I'll erase all boring pretenses and bad things with this sound.
何の取り柄も無い 僕にただ一つ
With no special talents to speak of,
少しだけど出来る事 心躍らせる
there is just one small thing I can do: make your heart race.
飾らない言葉 電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey my honest feelings with electronic sounds.
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね楽しくなるよ
Happy Synthesizer, see? It's getting fun.
涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
I'll play a melody to wipe away tears.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない 別に自分に素直になればいい
You don't have to act tough, just be true to yourself.
何の取り柄も無い 僕にただ一つ
With no special talents to speak of,
少しだけど出来る事 ちょっと照れるような
there's just one small thing I can do, slightly embarrassing—
単純な気持ち 電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey these simple feelings through electronic sounds.
みんなー！
Everyone!
ホロライブということで、
Hololive, so...
えー、このライブ、5期生獅白ぼたんですー！
um, this live stream is by 5th gen Shishiro Botan!
今日は、え、1周年記念で
Today, for my 1-year anniversary,
特別にアイドルっていうテーマで、珍しく歌メインの配信となっております。
as a special idol-themed stream, unusually for me, it will focus mainly on singing.
で、まあ、その曲ね、今歌ったんですけど、やっぱいろんな曲歌いたい、っていうことで
And well, I just sang that song, but I want to sing all sorts of songs, so
なんかね、デュエット曲とかもゲストさんを呼んで歌いたいなって思ってて
I was thinking I'd love to invite guests to sing duet songs together and such.
ゲストの方を呼んでいろんな曲をちょっと歌っていくっていう時間も設けたいなと
I wanted to make time to invite guests and sing various songs.
で、あー、びっくりした！
And—ah, you scared me!
え、びっくりした！見つかっちゃった！見つかっちゃった！
Eh, I was surprised! You found me! You found me!
ということで、今日の1人目のゲストです！
So, here is our first guest for today!
はい！犬神ころねと申します！
Hi! I'm Inugami Korone!
よろしくお願いします！ころね先輩！
Nice to meet you! Korone-senpai!
わー！おめでとう！
Yay! Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！1周年だー！
Thank you! It's the 1st anniversary!
というわけで、楽しい時間だった！
So, we're having such a fun time!
ありがとうございます！またね！
Thank you very much! See you again!
あ、あれ？まだある感じ？まだある感じ？
Huh? Are we still going? Is there more?
今日はね、アイドルっていうことで、あ、忘れかけていたことだ、ころね先輩にもアイドルをしていただいて。
Today is about idols, so—ah, I almost forgot—we'll have Korone-senpai act as an idol too.
一緒に？ 今の、でもね、もうアイドルしてるね！
Together? But wait, you're already acting like an idol!
してるでしょ！うん！
I am, right? Yeah!
すごい！一緒にアイドルできるの？
Amazing! Can we be idols together?
そう！だからね、今日はね、ちょっところね先輩と歌いたい曲を用意してきたので、歌っていただけると大変嬉しいです。
Yeah! So today, I prepared a song I'd love to sing with Korone-senpai, so I'd be super happy if you'd sing it with me.
なになに？なになに？
What is it? What is it?
じゃあ、早速いきます？
Shall we get right into it?
いく！
Let's go!
はい、分かりました！じゃあタイトルコールいきますよ！
Got it! Then let's do the title call!
ダンゼン！ふたりはプリキュア！
DANZEN! Futari wa Precure!
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリキュア プリキュア プリティでキュアキュア ふたりはプリキュア～！
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, pretty with cure-cure, the two of us are Pretty Cure~!
一難去って、また一難 ぶっちゃけありえない！！
One danger coming after another, totally unbelievable!!
制服着ててもふたりは めちゃくちゃタフだし
Even in our school uniforms, we're both amazingly tough,
お互いピンチを乗り越えるたび 強く近くなるね
and every time we overcome a pinch together, we grow stronger and closer.
your best! my best! 生きているから失敗なんてめじゃない！
Your best! My best! We're alive, so failure is no big deal!
笑う門に福来るでしょ！ ネガティブだってぶっ飛ぶー！
It seems good luck comes to those who smile! Send negative feelings flying~!
生命の花咲かせて！ 思いきりもっとバリバリ！
Let the flower of life bloom! With everything we've got, let's work even harder!
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリキュア プリキュア プリティでキュアキュア ふたりはプリキュア～！
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, pretty with cure-cure, the two of us are Pretty Cure~!
たまには放課後の本音とおしゃべりベリータイム
Sometimes after-school honest talks and chitchat, very time
恋する乙女の ビタミン剤だもん！
A vitamin supplement for a girl in love!
闇夜に浮かんだ虹の架け橋 ここにここに降りて降りて奇跡！
A rainbow bridge floating in the dark night, descend, descend right here, a miracle!
your best! my best! 全力だから友情愛情最高！
Your best! My best! We're giving it our all, so friendship and love are the best!
論理より証拠の輝く笑顔 必殺技でハートキュア！
A dazzling smile is better proof than logic, heart cure with a special move!
瞳に星映して 思いっきり
Reflecting stars in our eyes, with all our might
もっとキラキラ！
Sparkling even brighter!
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリキュア プリキュア プリティでキュアキュア ふたりはプリキュア～！
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, pretty with cure-cure, the two of us are Pretty Cure~!
明日は明日の風吹く まじ意味わかんない！
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow, I seriously don't get it!
今しかできない宿題 頑張らなくっちゃ！
Homework that can only be done now, we've got to work hard!
万物のからでも愛してる
Even from the shell of all creation, I love you
夢は夢を生きてる
Dreams live as dreams
力マックスハー！
Power Max Heart!
Yeah, you're best, my best 生きてるんだから失敗なんてない
Yeah, you're best, my best, living life so failures don't matter
笑う門に服着たあるでしょ ネガティブだってふっ飛ばす
Good luck comes to those who smile, blowing negativity away!
命の花咲かせて 思い切りもっとバリバリ
Let the flower of life bloom, going full throttle!
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Precure, Precure, Precure, Precure
プリキュリエ！キュアキュア ふたりは プリキュア！
Precure! Cure Cure, the two of us are Precure!
プリキュア プリキュア マックスハー！
Precure, Precure, Max Heart!
イェーイ！お疲れ様！
Yay! Good job!
ありがとうございました！もう俺たちか！歌って歌って！
Thank you very much! Are we already up? Sing, sing!
え、完全にアイドルだったよね？ね、完全にアイドルだった！
Huh, that was totally idol-like, right? Right, totally idols!
なので今からアイドルのね、撮影会なんかを
So from now on, we're gonna do an idol photo shoot session
え、一緒に撮った？スクショ？え、初めてだよね？のっけてね。
Huh, did you take pictures together? Screenshots? First time, right? Post 'em.
あ、そう！たぶん3Dで一緒にやるのは初めてだ！
Ah, right! It's probably our first time doing it together in 3D!
レア、レア映像、レア映像だよみんな。
Rare, rare footage, rare footage everyone.
あ、じゃあこの後ろの画像みたいに、あ、これね？
Ah, then like the image behind us, ah, this?
これ、こうか？あ、でもこう見えるから。あ、いいじゃん！かぶってる感じじゃんこれ。
This, like this? Ah, but you can see it. Ah, nice! It's like overlapping.
あ、こ、こうか？これだか？こんな感じ？撮れてる？撮れてる？
Ah, l-like this? Is this it? Like this? Did we get it? Did we get it?
こうか？オッケー！オッケー！撮れたか？撮れたね！みんな撮れた？撮れたね！
Like this? Okay! Okay! Did we get it? Got it! Did everyone get it? Got it!
え、じゃあ次次次！次時はちょっとなんか、やっぱりこう、戦うみたいな感じでさ、プリキュアみたいなさ。
Huh, then next, next, next! Next time, kinda like, fighting, like Precure.
プリキュアみたいな。よっ。こうかな？あ、かっこいいかも。かっこいい？
Like Precure. Yo. Like this? Ah, might be cool. Cool?
かっこいいかも。キリッ。キリッ！キリ！かっこいい？どうだろう、撮れたかな？撮れた？撮れたね！
Might be cool. Sharp. Sharp! Sharp! Cool? I wonder, did we get it? Got it? Got it!
かっこいいの撮れました？撮れた？なんかあるかな？すっ
Did you get a cool one? Got it? Is there anything? Whoosh
なんか、すっ。どうしよう。あ、なんかさ、ジャンプした瞬間撮ってもらおう。
Like, whoosh. What should we do? Ah, let's have them take a picture the moment we jump.
あ、いいよ！せーの、せーの！取れたかな？取れた？
Ah, sure! Ready, set! Did we get it? Got it?
多分みんなボタン連打してる。あ、ボタンだけにね！ボタンだけにね！
Probably everyone's mashing buttons. Ah, only buttons! Only buttons!
ちょっと、くそつまらないこと言っちゃった。あ、あれやって、あのさ、ガオガオポーズ。
I just said something super boring. Ah, do that, you know, the roar roar pose.
ガオ、犬かぞ、犬、犬かどうしだからね。実は猫かなんです。
Gao, dog kazo, dog, dog companions after all. Actually it's a cat.
カット、カットでお願いします。カットで！カットで！今日だけ、今日だけ犬だから！ガオー！
Cut, please do cut. Cut! Cut! Only today, only today I'm a dog! Roar!
カットしました？今日だけ、今日だけ犬だからね！今日だけ限定ですから！
Did you cut? Only today, because today I'm a dog! Only today limited edition!
他になんか、他に何か、あ、やる？はしご。
Anything else, anything else, ah, do? Ladder.
はしご！はしご！撮れた？撮れた？はしご。あ、いいね、いいね。あ、いいね。
Ladder! Ladder! Got it? Got it? Ladder. Ah, nice, nice. Ah, nice.
いい感じ、いい感じ！いい感じ？じゃああと、あと、あと、あと、あとね。
Good feel, good feel! Good feel? Then more, more, more, more.
こうね、まだ時間平気だよ！平気？1時間も2時間も大丈夫？マジ？うん。平気だよ！
Like this, we still have time! Okay? One or two hours is fine? Really? Yup. It's fine!
でもね、ちょっとね、そろそろ、やだ！次の方の、やだ！すみません、あの
But you know, sort of, soon, no! The next person's, no! Excuse me, um
じゃあここにおいで。あの、次の方のもちょっとお時間もありますんで
Then come here. Um, the next person also has some time, so
やだ！押してますんで！やだ！どうせね、ありがとうございました！お疲れ様でした！
No! We're running late! No! Anyway, thank you very much! Good job!
めちゃめちゃお疲れ様でした！あ、やだ！帰って、帰って帰って帰って！
Great job! Ah, no! Go back, go back go back go back!
バイバーイ！帰って帰って帰って！
Bye-bye! Go back go back go back!
あー、ころね先輩買っちゃったけどまた今度一緒に歌ってもらおっかな。
Ah, Korone-senpai left, but I wonder if she'll sing with me again next time.
じゃあちょっとね、次次は、今日はアイドルということでぴったりの歌をちょっとね持ってきたんで、よかったらみんなも一緒にコールをねしてもらえたら嬉しいかなと思います。
Well then, next up, today as an idol song, I brought a song that fits perfectly, so I'd be glad if you could all call along with me.
じゃあ早速次の歌いってみましょう！私！アイドル宣言！
Then let's go right to the next song! I'm! Idol declaration!
可愛くてごめん とびきりの愛を届け
Sorry for being so cute, sending my utmost love
よろしいければね
If you wouldn't mind
宜しければ名前だけでも…
Even if it's just my name...
覚えてって下さい m(_ _)m
Please remember it m(_ _)m
レッスン開始！
Lesson start!
意気込むけれど… 歌って 踊って ヘトヘト
I'm fired up, but... singing, dancing, exhausted
比較される事もあるけど 私は私で ありたい
Sometimes I get compared, but I want to be myself
本気出さなきゃ 響かないんだ ファンの心を 掴みたいんだ
If I don't give my all, it won't resonate. I want your hearts!
だから スタート全開 飛ばしますよ
So full throttle from the start, I'll blast through!
(You're my angel！！)
(You're my angel!!)
可愛くね とびきりの愛よ届け！
Super cute, delivering my absolute best love!
宜しければ名前だけでも… 覚えてって下さい m(_ _)m
Even if it's just my name... please remember it m(_ _)m
あざとくね とびきりのスマイルで！
Crafty and cute, with an extraordinary smile!
宜しければ推しにしちゃって… くれませんかね？なんてね
If you'd like, make me your oshi? Just kidding!
ちょっぴりマジなのは 期待していいですか？
Can you expect a little sincerity from me?
(ハイ！)
(Hai!)
人生変える そんな一日 憧れ 夢見た ステージ
A day that changes your life, the stage I dreamed of
オシャレ？ 流行り？ 追いつけなくて 言い訳 弱音も
Fashionable? Trendy? I can't keep up, making excuses
出ちゃうよ 向いてないかな？愛想悪いし
and complaints. Am I unsuited? I'm unfriendly,
こんなアイドル 他にいないし でもね 絶対絶対 見返すんだ！
and there's no idol like me. But I'll prove them wrong!
(You're my angel！！)
(You're my angel!!)
愛してね “日本一”夢見てる 宜しければ 合いの手一つ
Love me, dreaming of being Japan's best! If you don't mind,
入れてやって下さい (ハイ！)
throw in a call-and-response! (Hai!)
手を上げて 視線独り占めして！ 宜しければ 愛を恵んで
Raise your hands and hog attention! If you don't mind, shower love
くれるませんか？ なんてね 絶対後悔 させませんよ
won't you? Just kidding! I'll never let you regret it,
マジでねっ！！
Seriously!!
(ハイ！)
(Hai!)
今もステージは胸がキュッと熱くなる 揺れる景色焼き付けて 歌う声に愛を込める
Even now, my chest gets hot on stage, burning this scenery and pouring love into my voice
ギター！ 響く歓声 気持ち高鳴る
Guitar! Resounding cheers, my heart beating fast.
これは証明 私ここだよ いくよ？絶対絶対
This is proof, I'm right here! Ready? Absolutely,
声出してねっ (You're my angel！！)
raise your voices! (You're my angel!!)
可愛くね とびきりの愛よ届け！ 宜しければ名前だけでも…
Super cute, delivering my best love! Even if just my name...
覚えてってください m(_ _)m (ハイ！)
please remember it m(_ _)m (Hai!)
あざとくね とびきりのスマイルで！宜しければ推しにしちゃって… くれませんかね？なんてね
Crafty and cute, with an extraordinary smile! If you'd like, why not make me your oshi? Just kidding!
ちょっぴりマジなのは 期待していいですか？ (ハイ！)
Can you expect a little sincerity from me? (Hai!)
はーい！という ことで、えー3曲 歌ってきました。
Hii! So, um, I've sung three songs.
ま、やっぱり今日はね、アイドルがテーマなのでアイドル宣言は外せないかなと思ってたんですよね。
Since today's theme is idols, I figured I couldn't skip "Watashi, Idol Sengen".
じゃあちょっとね、次、あれ？ あれ、なんかすっごい美味しそうな匂いがする。
Now, um, next—huh? Wait, I smell something super delicious.
おら！ おら！ 食材じゃねえぞ！ おら！ まちがえ！ きーん！
Hey! Hey! I'm not ingredients! Hey! Wait! Whoops! Kiiin!
ということで、次のあ、食材じゃねえだろ！ まちがえ！
Anyway, the next—ah, you're not ingredients! My bad!
ジンギスカンはたけ先輩です！ 食材じゃねえだろ！ まちがえ！
It's Jingisukan Watame-senpai! You're not ingredients! My bad!
ちょっとすみからごめんなさいね。美味しそうな匂いがちょっとちらちらちらちら…いやちょっとずっと待ってたんだけど。
Sorry for cutting in from the corner. That delicious smell kept drifting over... Well, I've been waiting here the whole time.
あ、本当ね！ ごめんなさいね。ありがとうございます。今日は私たちのお休週年に…
Ah, really! I'm so sorry. Thank you so much. Today, for our 1st anniversary...
おめでとね。
Um...
おめでとうございます!
Happy anniversary!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
いやなんかね、もうもう1年なのかっていう
Yeah, you know... It's already been a year?
いや…ねえ…！
Yeah...
気分なんですけど…ねえ！
It feels like it, but also doesn't!
ねえ、今日はね、もうアイドルがテーマなんで
So today's theme is "Idol,"
わため先輩にもちょっとアイドルになってもらおうかな。
I want Watame-senpai to act like an idol too!
やっちゃうかな、きゅぴっ。
Shall we do it? Cute...
あ、かわいい！これは食べ甲斐がありますね。
Ah, cute! This is definitely eatable!
(笑)
(Laughter)
やめろ！食べれないじゃない！
Stop it! It's not eatable!
じゃあ今日はねちょっとね、えー、わためと一緒に歌いたい歌がありまして。
So today, Watame and I have a song we'd love to sing together.
私たちいつも、あの肉食系と草食系じゃないですか。
We usually do meat-eating and herbivore-eating genres, right?
そうですね。
That's right.
で、ちょっとね、理系っぽい歌。
So, a bit of a... science-y song?
お、理系？理系っぽい歌？
Science? Science-y song?
理系じゃなくても大丈夫？
Is it okay even if it's not science?
大丈夫です。文系でも大丈夫です。
It's fine! Arts is fine too!
何系でも大丈夫です。何でも！はい。
As long as it's any "kei," it's fine!
じゃあちょ、そう言うことですね、はい、歌っていきたいかなと思います。
So, with that said, we'd like to sing it!
オッケー！
Okay!
じゃあ、いいですか？アイドルコール一緒にお願いします！
Ready? Idol call with everyone, please!
はい！
Yes!
せーの、チューリングラブ！
Ready, set, Turing Love!
あー、恋の定義がわからない
Ah, I don't know the definition of love
まずスキって基準もわからない
First of all, I don't know the standard
要は、恋してる時が恋らしい
In short, I'm in love when I'm in love
客観? 主観? エビデンススプリーズ!
Objective? Subjectivity? Evidence, please!
愛は計算じゃ解けない
Love cannot be solved by calculation
まず普通の計算も解けない
First, we can't solve ordinary calculations
要は、そんな状態が愛らしい
In short, such a state is adorable
アイノウ? ユウノウ?
I know? You know?
もう大体事象においてQがあってAを出して解けるのに
Most of the time, Q has an A and you can solve it,
勘違いって間違って解のないこの気持ちはなんだろう (検証は不明瞭)
but what is this feeling without a solution? (Verification is unclear)
DAZING!! モーションは相対性にステイ
Dazing!! Motion stays in relativity
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love - a mellow that can't be solved even if you stare
ワットイズラブ いま123で証そうか
What is Love - now 1, 2, 3, let's prove it
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン (クエスチョン!)
Questions created with words (Question!)
ハートで高鳴るアンサー (アンサー!)
Answers that roar with a heart (Answer!)
測ったって不確定性 ぼくらのBPM
Uncertainty measured by our BPM
チューリングラブ 穹に舞ったって信じないけど
Turing Love - I don't believe you flew in the air
フォーリンラブ 今はABCすらバグりそうだ
Foreign Love - now even ABC seems to be buggy
なんでか教えてオイラー (オイラー!)
Tell me somehow, Euler (Euler!)
感想聞かせてフェルマー (フェルマー!)
Tell me your impressions, Fermat (Fermat!)
予測不可能性 いま触れてみる
Let's touch on the unpredictability
さあ証明しよう (証明しよう) 間違いのないように
Let's prove (Let's prove) so that there's no mistake
証明しよう (証明しよう) この感情全部全部
Let's prove (Let's prove) all these emotions
証明しよう (証明しよう) 正解があるなら
Let's prove (Let's prove) if there is a correct answer
証明しよう (証明しよう) シンプルなQ.E.D.
Let's prove (Let's prove) simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい! (しよう!)
Today, I want to prove it! (Let's try!)
目に見えない 無理難題を ASAP!
Invisible, difficult tasks, ASAP!
導き出したい たどり着きたい 最適解へ
I want to lead it, I want to arrive at the optimal solution
なんだかんだからまれて ぶつかったちってって
No matter how many times I went empty, I hit it
不奇妙なこのアノマリーを解き明かす過程さえ必要条件です。
To unravel this mysterious anomaly, even the process is a necessary condition.
"三次元(立体)における二点AB間の距離を求めよ。"
"Find the distance between two points A and B in three dimensions (space)."
的な感じだと思ってたのに
I thought it was that kind of feeling,
座標も公式も見当たらないし
but I couldn't see any coordinates or formulas,
参考資料にも載っていないから
and since it's not in the reference materials either,
きみと生み出してみせたいじゃん 三次元(世界)におけるこの気持ちの求め方
I want to show you how to find this feeling in 3D (the world).
丸だってバツだって不安にとってイクールで
0 and X are equal for anxiety,
近くなって遠くなって揺れるこの気持ちのハリも (条件は明瞭)
the needle of this feeling swaying closer and farther (the condition is clear).
Steppin'! エモーションは相対性ミステリー
Steppin'! Emotion is a relative mystery
チューリングラブ 騒ぎ出した胸の痛くなうほど
Turing Love - the pain in my chest that started making noise
証明はいま角度を増しているようだ
The proof still seems to be increasing its angle
曖昧も除外して最大の仮説
Excluding ambiguity, the largest hypothesis
いま、ふたりなら実証できそう
Now, if there's two of us, we can prove it
チューリングラブ 見つめあったってキリないメロウ
Turing Love - a mellow that doesn't hurt to stare
ワットイズラブ いま123で証そうか
What is Love - now 1, 2, 3, let's prove it
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン (クエスチョン!)
Questions created with words (Question!)
ハートで高鳴るアンサー (アンサー!)
Answers that roar with a heart (Answer!)
測ったって不確定性 ぼくらのBPM
Uncertainty measured by our BPM
チューリングラブ 穹に舞ったってその因果も
Turing Love - even if you fly in the air
フォーリンラブ 今はXYZまでわかりそうだ
Foreign Love - right now I can understand up to XYZ
確かめさせてピタゴラス (ピタゴラス!)
Let me confirm, Pythagoras (Pythagoras!)
確かになさせてリーマン (リーマン!)
Let me be sure, Riemann (Riemann!)
予測ずみ可変性 いま触れてみる
Let's touch on the predicted variability
さあ証明しよう (証明しよう) 間違いのないように
Let's prove (Let's prove) so that there's no mistake
証明しよう (証明しよう) この感情全部全部
Let's prove (Let's prove) all these emotions
証明しよう (証明しよう) 正解があるなら
Let's prove (Let's prove) if there is a correct answer
証明しよう (証明しよう) 臆測を超えて!
Let's prove (Let's prove) beyond guesswork!
さあ証明しよう (証明しよう) 間違いのないように
Let's prove (Let's prove) so that there's no mistake
証明しよう (証明しよう) この感情全部全部
Let's prove (Let's prove) all these emotions
証明しよう (証明しよう) 正解があるなら
Let's prove (Let's prove) if there is a correct answer
証明しよう (証明しよう) シンプルなQ.E.D.
Let's prove (Let's prove) simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい! (しよう!)
Today, I want to prove it! (Let's try!)
目に見えない 無理難題を ASAP!
Invisible, difficult tasks, ASAP!
導き出したい たどり着きたい 最適解へ
I want to lead it, I want to arrive at the optimal solution
なんだかんだからまれて ぶつかったちってって
No matter how many times I went empty, I hit it
不奇妙なこのアノマリーを解き明かす過程さえ必要条件です。
To unravel this mysterious anomaly, even the process is a necessary condition.
"三次元(立体)における二点AB間の距離を求めよ。"
"Find the distance between two points A and B in three dimensions (space)."
的な感じだと思ってたのに
I thought it was that kind of feeling,
座標も公式も見当たらないし
but I couldn't see any coordinates or formulas,
参考資料にも載っていないから
and since it's not in the reference materials either,
きみと生み出してみせたいじゃん 三次元(世界)におけるこの気持ちの求め方
I want to show you how to find this feeling in 3D (the world).
丸だってバツだって不安にとってイクールで
0 and X are equal for anxiety,
近くなって遠くなって揺れるこの気持ちのハリも (条件は明瞭)
the needle of this feeling swaying closer and farther (the condition is clear).
Steppin'! エモーションは相対性ミステリー
Steppin'! Emotion is a relative mystery
チューリングラブ 騒ぎ出した胸の痛くなうほど
Turing Love - the pain in my chest that started making noise
証明はいま角度を増しているようだ
The proof still seems to be increasing its angle
曖昧も除外して最大の仮説
Excluding ambiguity, the largest hypothesis
いま、ふたりなら実証できそう
Now, if there's two of us, we can prove it
チューリングラブ 見つめあったってキリないメロウ
Turing Love - a mellow that doesn't hurt to stare
ワットイズラブ いま123で証そうか
What is Love - now 1, 2, 3, let's prove it
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン (クエスチョン!)
Questions created with words (Question!)
ハートで高鳴るアンサー (アンサー!)
Answers that roar with a heart (Answer!)
測ったって不確定性 ぼくらのBPM
Uncertainty measured by our BPM
チューリングラブ 穹に舞ったってその因果も
Turing Love - even if you fly in the air
フォーリンラブ 今はXYZまでわかりそうだ
Foreign Love - right now I can understand up to XYZ
確かめさせてピタゴラス (ピタゴラス!)
Let me confirm, Pythagoras (Pythagoras!)
確かになさせてリーマン (リーマン!)
Let me be sure, Riemann (Riemann!)
予測ずみ可変性 いま触れてみる
Let's touch on the predicted variability
さあ証明しよう (証明しよう) 間違いのないように
Let's prove (Let's prove) so that there's no mistake
証明しよう (証明しよう) この感情全部全部
Let's prove (Let's prove) all these emotions
証明しよう (証明しよう) 正解があるなら
Let's prove (Let's prove) if there is a correct answer
やー！
Yay!
最後さ、あの手振っただけでさ
At the end, just waving our hands...
気づいた？ あとから振ったんだけどさ、気づいた？
Did you notice? I waved afterward, did you notice?
まあ、気づいた。すれ違ってたよな。すれ違っちゃったと思った。
Well, I noticed. We passed right by each other. I thought we missed each other.
まあ、あるあるだね。あるだね。
Well, that happens. It definitely does.
でね、ちょっとね、まだ時間あるからさ、あの、スクショタイムなんかどうでしょう？ いいねー。
And you know, we still have some time, so, how about a screenshot time? That sounds great!
なんか、なんかポーズある？やりたいポーズ。やりたいポーズある？何かる？
Do you have a pose in mind? A pose you want to do? Is there one?
いつもさ、いつもなんかこう、こう、こういう感じじゃん、いつも。逆、逆は？
Usually, it's like this, right? What about the reverse?
ギャー！
Aah!
もっと怖がってよ！ もっとうー！
Be more scared! More ooh!
もっと顔がねー！ もっと顔がねー！ あー！
More face! More face! Aah!
笑顔なんだな。
You're smiling, though!
怖がって！ う、ほんと。怖がってるよ、こわいこわい。
Be scared! Ooh, really. I am scared, so scary.
もう一回見せてあげる。うー！ うー！ めっちゃ怖がってる！ よしよ、助けてー！ すごい！
I'll show you again. Ooh! Ooh! You look so scared! There there, help me! Amazing!
これぐらいの。もう一回やっていい？ もう一回やっていい？
About this much. Can we do it one more time? Can we do it again?
ダー！ うわー！
Da! Whoa!
なんか怖くなさそうなんだよね。
Somehow you don't look very scared.
なんかさ、なんかさ、なんかちょっと余裕があるんだよ。ちょっと余裕あったね。
Somehow, you know, there's a bit of leeway. You had a bit of leeway.
なんて？なんでよ？ え、他でも、まあやっぱり一周年記念、なんかちょっと可愛いポーズしたいな。
What? Why? Well, since it's the 1st anniversary, I want to do a cute pose.
したいね。え、なんか、チューリングラブのときのさ、チューリング、ラブ、ラブ、ラブ。
I'd love to. Um, like during Turing Love, Turing, Love, Love, Love.
え、いいの？いいよ。ハートにするの。
Eh, is that okay? Sure. Making a heart.
ああー！ハートになっちゃった。
Ahh! It turned into a heart.
見えるか？見えるか？難しいな。なんとか、なんとか、ハートに。
Can you see it? Can you see it? It's hard. Somehow, make it a heart.
みんながハートに行くのを見てください。あ、あ、できない！できたんじゃない？どう？
Please watch everyone go to the heart. Ah, ah, can't do it! Didn't we make it? How is it?
誰がゾンビのハートだ！それがハートなんだ。われわれのハートだ！
Whose heart is a zombie's?! That is a heart. It's our heart!
背中合わせとか。かっこいい。
Back-to-back or something. Cool.
たまにはかっこいいワタメもちょっと見たいね。かっこいい。どう？あ、いいね。かっこいいよワタメ。いいね。かっこいい！おお、いいいいいい。あんしゃだね。みんな撮ってる？
Sometimes I want to see a cool Watame too. Cool. How is it? Ah, nice. Cool, Watame. Nice. Nice. Cool! Oh, very nice. That's safe. Is everyone taking pictures?
大丈夫？きゅう、きゅう、かっこいいな。いいね。いいね。
Are you okay? Kyuu, kyuu, so cool. Nice. Nice.
じゃあね、ワタメさんちょっとね、申し訳ない。ちょっとね、そろそろ何？ お時間のほうが迫ってきているらしいんですよ。
Well Watame-san, I'm sorry, but it seems our time is running out.
わかんない。お時間何？わかんない。あ、ちょっと閉店のお時間。閉店？
I don't know. What time? I don't know. Ah, closing time. Closing?
そうだ。絶対ここにいろ。ずっといろ。いっしょあ、やめてー！行かないで！行かないで！
That's right. Stay here forever. Stay here together—ah, stop! Don't go! Don't go!
くそー、逃げられたな。ちょっとワタメはまた今度追いかけるとして。じゃあ次の曲なすけれども、ええとね、これね、私がね、ボカロの歌を歌うことって、まあ今日1曲目あのハッピーシンセサイザを歌ったと思うんですけど、あんまりなくて普段。でも今日はちょっと好きなボカロの曲がね、あったので歌わせてもらおうかなと思います。それでは、ええ聞いてください。帝国少女。
Damn, she got away. I'll chase Watame down next time. Well, for the next song... um, you know, me singing Vocaloid songs—well, I sang Happy Synthesizer as the first song today, but I don't usually do it much. But today, since there was a Vocaloid song I really like, I'd like to sing it for you. So then, please listen. Teikoku Shoujo.
頭痛的都市構想 浮ついた世のシーンでメロディに
Throbbing urban concept floating in a fickle world's scene to the melody
雑踏の中息衝いたTrap ChiptuneとNeon アラカルト
Trap breathing in the hustle and bustle, chiptune and neon à la carte
感傷的都市逍遥 弗らついた夜のミームとメロディ
Sentimental urban roaming, staggered night's meme and melody
彷徨って行き着いた路地裏の闇夜に溶ける
Wandering and ending up melting into the dark night of the back alleys
本能的都市抗争 騒々しい銀のホールでファジーに
Instictive urban conflict in a noisy silver hall fuzzily
喧騒の中褪せるVaporwave Makina エトセトラ
Vaporwave fading in the hubbub, Makina et cetera
絶対的都市抗争
Absolute urban conflict,
浮ついた今日のあいづをバターに
turning today's fickle signal into butter,
強がって噛み付いた 響える都市のシステム
biting down defiantly, the echoing city system.
純金の欠乏感を左耳にぶら下げて
Hanging a sense of deficiency of pure gold from my left ear,
芳香性の憂鬱感をまとったら
and wrapping myself in a fragrant melancholy,
抗菌性の停滞感を両手の爪にちりばめて
embedding a sense of antibacterial stagnation into my nails.
どうせ何も起こることのないこの夜に
In this night where nothing will happen anyway,
朽ちていく身体と心をつれ 一人あてなく漂っていくの
taking my decaying body and heart, drifting aimlessly alone.
形骸的残響に縛され 滅び行く都市を這い回るゾンビ
Bound by skeletal reverberations, zombies crawling through the perishing city.
どんなにどんなに夜に堕ちても 明日の光が世界を染めてく
No matter how deep into the night I fall, tomorrow's light stains the world.
蘇る私は 帝国少女
Reviving, I am an Imperial Girl.
盲目的都市幻想
Blind urban illusion,
ひしめき合うスナップと互いをクロエ
snaps jostling together and crossing each other.
私をちょっと狂わせるPUSHER Wave Pablo エトセトラ
PUSHER, Wave, Pablo, and et cetera that drive me slightly mad.
恋愛的都市様相 目眩く夜とジーンのシャワーに
Romantic urban aspects, drenched in a dazzling night and gin shower,
浸り濡れた指の先でなぞる恋のシニカル
tracing the cynicism of love with wet fingertips.
金剛性の背徳感を薬の指に光らせて
Making a sense of adamantine depravity shine on my ring finger,
伸縮性の優越感に袖を通して
slipping my sleeves through a sense of elastic superiority.
後天性の先入観で両目の淵を彩った
Adorning the rims of both eyes with acquired preconceptions,
違う人との部屋で夢を見るならもう
if I'm going to dream in a room with someone else, then no more.
私の身体と心を傷付けた罪を償いなさいよ 衝動的感情に流されて行き着く先はクライクライ夜
Atone for the sin of wounding my body and heart! Swept away by impulsive emotion, where I end up is a cry-cry night.
あんなにあんなに縛られたのは あなたに愛して欲しかっただけ
Being bound so, so tightly was simply because I wanted you to love me.
泣き濡れる私は 嗜虐少女
Weeping and soaking, I am a sadistic girl.
もう遣る瀬無い浮かんでき日々も 揺れる摩天楼に抱かれて
Even days where I feel helpless, held in swaying skyscrapers,
ビルに見まえる夜空の星に願いを込め込む こんな夜に
pouring my wishes into the stars of the night sky visible over the buildings, on a night like this.
朽ちていく身体と心をつれ 一人あてなく漂っていくの
Taking my decaying body and heart, drifting aimlessly alone.
形骸的残響に縛され 滅び行く都市を這い回るゾンビ
Bound by skeletal reverberations, zombies crawling through the perishing city.
どんなにどんなに夜に堕ちても 明日の光が世界を染めてく
No matter how deep into the night I fall, tomorrow's light stains the world.
ミルラインなどどうでもいいのよ こんなにこんなに愛したい場所は何度も何度も吐いた道のサイド
Miline and all that doesn't matter. The place I wanted to love so much is the roadside where I threw up time and again.
結局狂気に追われるゾンビ 私の身体と心置き去りで行くわ
Zombies ultimately chased by madness. I'll leave my body and heart behind as I go.
帝国少女の傷 あなたの笑顔も声も全部 ここに置いていくわ 帝国少女
The scars of the Imperial Girl... Your smile, your voice, I'll leave them all right here, Imperial Girl.
はい、ということで皆さんありがとうございました！
Alright, thank you everyone!
もう半分は終わったのかな、用意してた曲。
Half of the prepared songs are already done, I guess?
じゃあそろそろあれかな、次のゲストの方、待ち合わせしてたんだけどな。
Well then, it's about time for... the next guest, whom I arranged to meet.
あれ？
Huh?
なんかある？
Is there something?
あー！うわー！
Ahh! Whoa!
ああ、尻尾引っ張られてびっくりした。
Ah, I got startled when my tail was pulled.
いいお尻してるね。
You've got a nice butt.
よもぎだっても... いいお尻してるね！
Yomogi too... has a nice butt!
ということで、次の3人目のゲストは猫又おかゆ先輩です！
And now, our third guest is Nekomata Okayu-senpai!
呼んでくれてありがとう！おかゆだよ〜
Thanks for calling me! It's Okayu~
ということで、1周年記念ありがとうございます、きていただいて。
So, thank you so much for coming for the 1st anniversary.
いやいや、こちらこそおめでとう、1周年！
No, no, congratulations on your 1st anniversary!
早いものでもうちょっとね、1周年、あっという間だったね。
Time flies, it's already been a year, in the blink of an eye.
なんか、おかゆ先輩と並ぶとさ、なんかちょっとあれっぽくね、先輩と…
Somehow, standing next to Okayu-senpai, it feels a bit like senior and...
あ、先輩というか、私チンチクリンすぎてやばい。
Ah, rather than senior, I'm way too short and tiny, it's terrible.
あれ？私の方が全然先輩なんだぞ？
Huh? I'm way more senior, you know?
なんでこんなに大きいんだよ！
Why are you so big?!
なんかこれじゃ私がボタンちゃんのさ、射程の何？手の部分みたいな、手の部分？弟の部分？
It's like I'm Botan-chan's firing range... hand part, younger brother part?
おい、うちのボタン姉さんに何か用か？
Hey, you got business with our Big Sis Botan?
ほら ぼたん お姉さんに
Look, Botan, to your big sister...
ほら あ かかってこいよ
Look, ah, bring it on!
ぼたんお姉さんに話しがあるなら まず僕に声をかけてくんないと困るんだけど
If you have something to talk about with Botan-oneesan, you gotta talk to me first, or I'm in trouble.
お母さん方に手を出してもらおう ただじゃおかないか
Let's get our mamas involved... we won't let you off easy!
ぼたんお姉さんなんか呼ぼうよ
Let's call Botan-oneesan!
うわあ かかってこいよ
Woah, bring it on!
今日はな 二人でな アイドルなんだよ
Today, the two of us are idols!
アイドルって何だ なんか歌うのか
Idols? What's that? Are we gonna sing?
歌うぞ 今日はなお母さん先輩とな アイドルとしてちょっとかっこいい曲歌うんだ
We're gonna sing! Today, with Mama-senpai, as idols, we're gonna sing a pretty cool song.
何歌うんだ 教えてくれよ
What are you singing? Tell me!
じゃあ一緒にタイトルコールお願いして いいかな
Then, can we ask you to do the title call together?
いいよ
Sure!
いくぞ
Let's go!
じゃあいくぞ
Alright, here we go!
せーの LOSER
Ready, set! LOSER!
いつもどおりの通り通り こんな日々もはや懲り懲り
As usual, alone. I'm sick and tired of days like this.
どこにも行きやしないのに 夢見ておやすみ
I can't go anywhere, but I'll dream and go to sleep.
いつでも僕らはこんな風に ぼんくらな夜に飽き飽き
We're always like this, tired of these dull nights.
また踊り踊り出す 明日に出会うためにさようなら
Goodbye, so we can meet tomorrow and dance again.
歩き回ってやっと着いた ここはどこだ楽園か
I walked around and finally arrived. Is this paradise?
今となっちゃもうわからない
Now I don't know anymore.
四半世紀の結果出た 青い顔のスーパースターが
The result of a quarter century. A superstar with a pale face...
お腹すかして待ってる
...is waiting, hungry.
アイエムルーザー どうせだったら遠吠えだっていいだろう
I'm a loser, so I might as well howl.
もう一回もう一回行こうぜ僕らの声
Let's go again, let's go again, our voices.
アイエムルーザー ずっと前から聞こえてた
I'm a loser, I've been hearing it for a long time.
いつかポケットに隠した声が
The voice I hid in my pocket someday.
ああだこうだ知ったもんか さきざきの空は悪天候
I don't care about this or that, the sky ahead is stormy.
ほら窓から覗いた摩天楼からすりゃ塵のよう
Look, the skyscrapers peeking through the window are like dust to crows.
イアンもカートも昔の人よ 中指立ててもしょうがないの
Ian and Kurt, who never helped you are in the past - gone, You won't get anywhere with that middle finger act.
今勝ち上がるためのお勉強 おぼつかない表情 踊る阿呆に見る阿呆 我楽多から笑う阿呆
Those dancing fools, those staring fools, we're those shrewd laughing fools.
デカイ自意識抱え込んでいては もう摩耗 すり減って残るスパイク泥
Big ego weighing you down, worn out, spikes covered in mud.
膝抱えてもなんもねえ ほら長い前髪で前が見えねえ
Hugging your knees gets you nothing, long bangs blocking your vision.
笑っちまうね パッと沸き立って フワッと消えしちまうこんな輪廻 愛されたいならそう言おうぜ
Laughable, bubbling up and fading away in this circle of reincarnation, if you want to be loved, say so.
思ってるだけじゃ伝わらないね 永遠の淑女もそっぽ向いて
Just thinking it won't convey, even the eternal maiden looks away.
天国は遠く向こうの方へ ああ分かってるって深々転がる俺は負け犬
Heaven is far away ahead, ah I know, tumbling deep, I'm a loser.
ただどこでもいいから遠くへ行きたいんだ それだけなんだ
I just want to go somewhere far away, that's all.
耳をすませ遠くで今 響きだした音を逃すな
Listen carefully in the distance for the sound starting to echo now.
呼吸を整えて いつかは出会えるはずの
Regulate your breath, to the one you're bound to meet someday.
黄金色をしたアイオライトを きっと掴んで離すな
That golden iolite, grab it and never let go.
アイエムルーザー なんこともないならどうなったっていいだろう
I'm a loser, if nothing else so it's fine.
うだうだしてフラフラして いちいち今に灰左様なら
Keep messing, keep guessing, saying goodbye to the present.
アイエムルーザー きっといつだって願うまま進めロスタイムのその奥へ
I'm a loser, always advancing as wished into the depths of loss time.
愛されたいならそう言おうぜ 思ってるだけじゃ伝わらないね
If you want to be loved, say so, just thinking it won't convey.
永遠の淑女もそっぽ向いて 天国は遠く向こうの方へ
Even the eternal maiden turns away, heaven is far away.
愛されたいならそう言おうぜ 思ってるだけじゃ伝わらないね
If you want to be loved, say so, just thinking it won't convey.
永遠の淑女もそっぽ向いて 天国は遠く向こうの方へ
Even the eternal maiden turns away, heaven is far away.
ここらでひとつ踊ってみようぜ 夜が明けるまで転がっていこうぜ
Let's dance a bit here, roll until dawn.
聞こえてんなら声を出していこうぜ アイエムルーザー
If you can hear me, shout out, I'm a loser.
どうせだったら遠吠えだっていいだろう もう一回もう一回行こうぜ僕らの声
So what if it's a howl, let's go again, our voices.
アイエムルーザー ずっと前から聞こえてた いつかポケットに隠した声が
I'm a loser, I've been hearing it, the voice hidden in my pocket.
ここらでひとつ踊ってみようぜ 夜が明けるまで転がっていこうぜ
Let's dance a bit here, roll until dawn.
聞こえてんなら声を出していこうぜ アイエムルーザー
If you can hear me, shout out, I'm a loser.
どうせだったら遠吠えだっていいだろう もう一回もう一回行こうぜ僕らの声
So what if it's a howl, let's go again, our voices.
アイエムルーザー ずっと前から聞こえてた いつかポケットに隠した声が
I'm a loser, I've been hearing it, the voice hidden in my pocket.
ここらでひとつ踊ってみようぜ 夜が明けるまで転がっていこうぜ
Let's dance a bit here, roll until dawn.
聞こえてんなら声を出していこうぜ
If you can hear me, shout out.
ここらでひとつ踊ってみようぜ 夜が明けるまで転がっていこうぜ
Let's dance a bit here, roll until dawn.
聞こえてんなら声を出していこうぜ
If you can hear me, shout out.
え、うちらのルーザーどうだった？
So, how was our "LOSER"?
どうだった？おら！どうだった？おら！
How was it, huh? How was it, huh?
うちらのアイドルの見たか？
Did you see our idol side?
アイドルだった？おら！
Were we idols, huh?
おらおら！
Hey, hey!
カメラこっち寄ってこいよ！こっち寄ってこいよ！
Camera, get closer over here! Get closer!
スクショ、ちゃんとスクショ！
Take screenshots, proper screenshots!
やめ...大丈夫かな？
Stop... Is this okay?
そんなとこ抑えないの！
Don't hold onto places like that!
こうやってね、一緒に並んだりするの初めてだからさ！
Since it's our first time standing in a line like this!
おら！おい寄ってこいよもっと！がっちり上等だおら！
Ora! Hey, get closer! Bring it on, ora!
がっちり上等だおら！
Bring it on, ora!
がっちり上等だおら！こんな近づくことない！こんな近づくアイドルの内側全部おら！
Bring it on, ora! We never get this close! Botan, showing all of an idol's inner self, ora!
カメラの意志を無視するアイドル全部おら！
Ignoring the camera's intentions completely, idols, ora!
ぼたんちゃん、僕、もうそろそろ行かなきゃいけない時間みたいだ。
Botan-chan, it looks like it's almost time for me to go.
やだ！
No way!
ぼたんちゃんが？そういうキャラだっけぼたんさん？
Botan-chan is? Was that your character, Botan-san?
もっといじょうよ、先輩。おかゆのちょっとの？
Tease me more, Senpai. Okayu's a little...?
そう、かわいいねよしよしよしよしよしよし！でも帰る。
So cute, there, there, there, there! But I'm going back.
ああ！おかゆ先輩！やだ！ああ待って！
Ah! Okayu-senpai! No! Ah, wait!
はあ、おかゆ先輩が帰ってしまった。
Hah, Okayu-senpai has gone home.
いやあ、でも今日は本当に3名のゲストの方にお越しいただきありがとうございます。
Man, but today, thank you so much to our three guests for coming.
ということで、ここからはね、獅白ぼたんのソロになりますけれども、
So from here on, it will be Shishiro Botan's solo,
次の曲はですね、まあちょっとしっとりした感じの、ちょっと、うーん、でもなんか私が好きな曲を今日集めているので、ぜひ聞いていただければと思います。それでは行ってみましょう、「ルーマー」！
and the next song is a bit mellow, um, but since I've gathered songs I really like today, I hope you'll listen to it. Let's go, "Rumor"!
だいぶ夢中だね 笑えもしない
You're really into it, can't even crack a smile
この忌々しさ引き取って頂戴
Take this irritation off my hands
こんなイマイマシさ引き取って頂戴
Take this current annoyance off my hands
魔法みたいにさ
Just like a magic spell,
リセットされるのが早過ぎる
It resets way too fast.
霞がまだかかっているの
The fog is still hanging over,
それこそメンタルやられるよ
That's what really messes with your mental state.
ぶら下げて切り抜けるなんてどう
What if we just hang it down and push through?
嫌いになれない止めたいよ本当
I can't even hate you, I really want to stop.
どうにも手に負えない…認めるよ
It's too much to handle... I admit it.
歯痒くなるよ
It's getting frustrating.
想思通りの振る舞いも
Even the way you act just as I imagined,
すこぶるクールな your mind
Is so unbearably cool, your mind.
最高潮の touch 跳ね上がる heartbeat
At the peak of touch, my heartbeat surges.
溺れてしまう 戻れないくらい
Drowning in it, to the point of no return.
踏み込んで巡るのさ satellite
Stepping inside and spinning around like a satellite.
初めから分かっている
I knew it from the start.
薄っぺらだね
You're so shallow, huh.
あんまやな感じ
Such a nasty feeling,
気付いてないところが救い
The only saving grace is that you don't even realize it.
誤魔化し合う才能
A talent for playing dumb.
魔法みたいにさ
Just like magic,
本音の裏だね 真後ろ過ぎ
It's right behind your true feelings, too close behind.
際どいとこ突かれてるよ
You're poking at sensitive spots.
訴えたいのはこっちの方
I'm the one who wants to complain.
理想砕ける音と空色
The sound of shattering ideals and the color of the sky.
ろくでもないのに止めたいよ本当
You're good for nothing, yet I really want to stop.
どうにも手に負えない…認めるよ
It's too much to handle... I admit it.
歯痒くなるよ
It's getting frustrating.
想思通りの振る舞いも
Even the way you act just as I imagined,
すこぶるクールな your mind
Is so unbearably cool, your mind.
最高潮の touch 跳ね上がる heartbeat
At the peak of touch, my heartbeat surges.
溺れてしまう 戻れないくらい
Drowning in it, to the point of no return.
踏み込んで巡るのさ satellite
Stepping inside and spinning around like a satellite.
初めから分かっている
I knew it from the start.
間隙を埋めるほど
The more I try to fill the gaps,
導かれるのさ i'm greedy
The more I'm led on—yes, I'm greedy.
ほらあの呪いも悪くないだろなんて
Hey, even that curse doesn't seem so bad after all.
丸ごと何処か他所へやって
Throwing everything away somewhere else,
新しい期待で満たす
I fill my heart with new expectations.
いつだって執着だから
Because I'm always so persistent.
どうにも手に負えない…認めるよ
It's too much to handle... I admit it.
歯痒くなるよ
It's getting frustrating.
想思通りの振る舞いも
Even the way you act just as I imagined,
すこぶるクールな your mind
Is so unbearably cool, your mind.
最高潮の touch 跳ね上がる heartbeat
At the peak of touch, my heartbeat surges.
溺れてしまう 戻れないくらい
Drowning in it, to the point of no return.
踏み込んで巡るのさ satellite
Stepping inside and spinning around like a satellite.
初めから分かっている
I knew it from the start.
隙間を埋めるほど
The more I try to fill the gaps,
導かれるのさ satellite
The more I'm guided along like a satellite.
どうにも手に負えない…認めるよ
It's too much to handle... I admit it.
歯痒くなるよ
It's getting frustrating.
想思通りの振る舞いも
Even the way you act just as I imagined,
すこぶるクールな your mind
Is so unbearably cool, your mind.
最高潮の touch 跳ね上がる heartbeat
At the peak of touch, my heartbeat surges.
溺れてしまう 戻れないくらい
Drowning in it, to the point of no return.
踏み込んで巡るのさ satellite
Stepping inside and spinning around like a satellite.
初めから分かっている
I knew it from the start.
あっても あの ささやかな 始まりから始まって
Even so, it started from that modest beginning...
ってことでルーマーでした。
So that was Roomer.
それでは、えー、続いての曲を連続で行きましょう。聞いてください。
Well then, let's move right along to the next song. Please listen to...
海の幽霊。
"Ghost of the Sea."
開け放たれた　この部屋には誰もいない
In this wide-open room, there is no one here.
潮風の匂い　しみついた椅子がひとつ
A single chair soaked in the scent of the ocean breeze.
あなたが迷わないように　開けておくよ　軋む戸を叩いて
I'll leave it open so you won't get lost... Knock on the creaking door.
なにから話せばいいのか　わからなくなる
I don't even know what I should say anymore.
星が降る夜に　あなたにあえた
On a night when stars fall, I was able to meet you.
あの夜を忘れはしない
I will never forget that night.
大切なことは　言葉にならない
The most important things cannot be put into words.
夏の日に起きたすべて
Everything that happened on a summer day.
思いがけず光るのは　海の幽霊
Shining unexpectedly is the ghost of the sea.
うだる夏の日に　こずえが船を見送る
On sweltering summer days, treetops watch the ships depart.
いくつかの歌を唱う　花を散らして
Humming a few songs, scattering flowers.
あなたがどこかで笑う声が聞こえる　熱い頬の手触り
I hear your voice laughing somewhere, the warmth on my burning cheeks.
ねじれた道を進んだなら　その眸が開く
If you walk down the twisting path, those eyes will open.
離れ離れでも　ときめくものを
Whatever makes our hearts flutter even apart—
叫ぼう　今は幸せと
let's shout out, "I'm happy now!"
離れ離れでも　ときめくものを
Even when separated, what makes our hearts flutter—
叫ぼう　今は幸せと
Let's shout out, "I'm happy now!"
大切なことは　言葉にならない
The most important things cannot be put into words.
夏の日に起きたすべて
Everything that happened on a summer day.
星が降る夜に　あなたにあえた
On a night when stars fall, I was able to meet you.
あのときを忘れはしない
I will never forget that time.
大切なことは　言葉にならない
The most important things cannot be put into words.
夏の日に起きたすべて
Everything that happened on a summer day.
思いがけず光るのは　海の幽霊
Shining unexpectedly is the ghost of the sea.
風薫る砂浜で　また会いましょう
Let's meet again on the breeze-scented sandy beach.
はーい、皆さんありがとうございました。ということで「海の幽霊」歌わせていただきました。
Hi everyone, thank you so much! So that was me singing "Ghost of the Sea."
じゃあ、そろそろね、もうね、時間も過ぎてきているんですけれども、ここで告知タイムだーん！
Well then, it's getting close to that time, but here is the announcement time, bam!
やっほー！ふぁふぁふぁふぁふぁ～
Ya-hoo! Fafafafafa~
ということで、えー活動一周年記念の
So, the 1st anniversary merch
グッズが出ますので、一つずつ簡単に紹介していきます。
is coming out, so I'll briefly introduce them one by one.
じゃあまず一つ目なんですけど、えーこちらどん！
First up, um, here we go, ta-da!
プレミアムアクリルパネルです！えー出ますかね？はい。
The Premium Acrylic Panel! Can you see it? Yep.
こちら、あの普段出してるアクリルパネルよりちょっと豪華なものになります。
This one is a bit more luxurious than the acrylic panels we usually release.
ちょっとサインの文字が浮き出てるというか、パーツの一部として浮き出てる。
The signature text sort of stands out, like it's part of the design pieces.
今回は本当にトマリ先生にね、イラストを描いていただきましたんでぜひ飾ってください。
This time, Tomari-sensei drew a wonderful illustration for it, so please display it!
そして2つ目、こちらどん！
And second, here we go, ta-da!
ライブタオル！今日はね、
A live towel! Today, um,
今日はアイドルっていうテーマでやってるから、なんかライブっぽいグッズ欲しかったんですよ。
the theme is "idol," so I wanted some merchandise that felt like a live concert.
なのでちょっとライブタオルなるものを作ってみました。これ私のね、この袖、袖わかる？
So I tried making a live towel. Can you see my sleeve here?
袖の、この部分と似たタオルです。
It's a towel modeled after this part of my sleeve.
これ結構長くて、胸あたりまであるんでスポーツに使ってもよし、ライブ行くにもよし、外行くにもよし、家で使うもよし。
It's pretty long, reaching your chest. Great for sports, live shows, going out, or at home.
そして次これ、どん！
And next is this, ta-da!
で、ライブといえばやっぱり私キーホルダーのイメージがあって、
When you think of a live, I always picture a keychain,
なのでライブキーホルダーも作ってみました。こちらみなさんよかったら、
so I made a live keychain too. If you guys like it,
これもね、分かるかな？ここここの袖の部分の感じを表現しました。
can you tell? It expresses the look of the sleeve part here.
ぜひいろんなところに飾ってほしいですこれ。はい。
I hope you'll display it everywhere. Yes.
で、あとは記念フルボイスと、
And then, there's the anniversary full voice set,
えっと、フルセット購入特典の方に、あのサイン付き複製なんですが、複製付きサインのポストカードがついてくるんですが、
and for those who buy the full set, you get a replica postcard with a signature.
今回なんとサインがオリジナル、この一周年記念のライブに合わせて、オリジナルのサインになってます。
This time, the signature is original, tailored for this 1st anniversary live,
普段の獅白ぼたんのサインじゃないんです。
It's not my usual Shishiro Botan signature.
なのでちょっとレア感があるサインとなってます。アイドルっぽいサインにします。
So it's a rare one! I made it an idol-style signature.
ということで、フルセット購入特典となりますのでぜひ、あの全部買った方は大事に飾りってください。
So please take good care of it if you bought the whole set!
はい。えーそしてね、ちょっとね、紹介したいことが何点かあるんで紹介します。
Right. And there are a few things I'd like to announce, so let me share them.
えーと21時15分から私のファーストオリジナル曲、「Lioness' Pride」という曲なんですが、
At 21:15, my first original song, "Lioness' Pride," will premiere!
今週は私、えーとラミちゃん、ねねちゃん、私っていう、えー順番で今やってるじゃないですか一周年記念。
This week, Lamy-chan, Nene-chan, and me—that's the order we've been doing the 1st anniversary streams.
で、次ラストおまるん、おまるポルカなんなんですけども、いったん明日は、えーとホロライブ公式の配信で、ホロライブエラーが8時から放送予定となってますので、
And next is the last one, Omaru Polka. But first, tomorrow at 8:00 PM, Hololive Error will be broadcast on the official channel,
そちらを見てもらったから明後日、えーと16日の月曜日、えーおまるポルカのね、記念配信がありますので、そちらもぜひ8時からあるらしいのでよかったらチェックしてみてください。
so after watching that, the day after tomorrow on Monday the 16th, Omaru Polka's anniversary stream starts at 8:00 PM, so please check that out too.
はい、ありがとうございます。ちょっとお知らせ駆け足気味にはなってますけど、よかったらぜひ記念グッズはたぶんもう買えたりするかな？あるのでぜひお求めいただけると嬉しいです。オリジナル曲もよろしくお願いします。
Anniversary goods should be available now, so I'd be happy if you pick them up. And please look forward to the original song too!
じゃあそうだな、今日はみんな本当に見てくれてありがとうございます。あの、アイドル、今日はアイドルっていうテーマでね、やってきたんんですけど、最後もちょっとね頑張ってアイドルやるぞということでよろしくお願いします。
Thank you all for watching today. As we reach the end, I'll do my best to be an idol right to the end!
それでは最後の曲です、聴いてください。 幽霊東京
Now for the final song, please listen to "Ghost Tokyo."
完全無欠 輝く町の 灯り対象的な僕を見下ろす
The flawless, brightly shining town lights look down on my contrasting self.
あのビルの間を抜けた日の時出したね本当マジで
The moment I slipped out between those buildings, I truly met it—seriously.
僕の時間とこの世界をトレード 夜に沈む
Trading my time for this world, sinking into the night.
終点で家路をたどる
Following my way home at the end of the line,
僕の目に映るガラス窓にいたのは夢見た自分じゃなくて今にも泣き出してしまいそうな醜い闇の中一人孤独さまよっている
what was reflected in the glass window wasn't the self I dreamed of, but someone on the verge of tears, wandering alone in the ugly darkness.
大丈夫 いつか大丈夫になるなんて思う日々をいくつか重ねた
How many days have I spent telling myself that it'll be fine someday?
燦然と輝く街の灯り
A shining city's lights
対照的な僕を見下ろす
Looking down at me, contrasting
忘れてしまった
Even those wishes
あの願いさえも
I had forgotten...
思い出したときに
When I remembered them,
涙が落ちたのは
The tears that fell
この街がただ
Were simply because this city...
あんまりにも眩しいから
Was far too dazzling.
散々だって笑いながら
Laughing off how miserable it is,
嘆く大体的な日々のなか
Lamenting through these mostly unfulfilled days,
あの日の想いがフラッシュバック
The feelings of that day flash back.
気付けば朝まで開くロジック
Logic that stays open until morning before you know it,
僕の言葉を音に乗せて何度でも
Putting my words to sound over and over.
忘れてしまった
Even those days
あの願いさえも
I had forgotten...
それでも最後は
Even so, in the end,
それでもまだ先へ なんて思えるのは君がいるから
The reason I can think of going further is because you're here.
ねぇ こんな寂しい街で
Hey, in such a lonely city,
ねぇ
Hey...
燦然と輝く街の灯り
A shining city's lights
対照的な僕を見下ろす
Looking down at me, contrasting
あのビルの先 手を伸ばして
Reaching out beyond that building,
あの日の夢見た景色をなぞって
Tracing the scenery I dreamed of that day.
僕の時間とこの世界をトレード 明日を呼ぶ
Trading my time and this world, calling for tomorrow.
失くさずにいた 一番大事な想いよ
The most precious feelings I managed not to lose,
抱きしめたら不意に
When I hugged them close,
涙が落ちたのは
The tears that fell
この街がまだ 生きていたいと思うから
Were because I still want to live in this city.
君もそうでしょう
You feel the same way too, right?
みんなは、ありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
このあと21時15分からオリジナル曲、よかったら見てね！
After this at 21:15, my original song... check it out if you'd like!
またね、バーイバーイ！
See you later, bye-bye!